A story like mine has never been told.
Memoirs of a Geisha is a drama, romance, history film directed by Rob Marshall.
In the years before World War II, a penniless Japanese child is torn
from her family to work as a maid in a geisha house.
Sayuri, played by Zhang Ziyi.
Hatsumomo, played by Gong Li.
Mameha, played by Michelle Yeoh.
Chairman, played by Ken Watanabe.
Chiyo, played by Suzuka Ohgo.
Mother, played by Kaori Momoi.
Memoirs of a Geisha, released in Japan as Sayuri, is a 2005 American epic period drama film directed by Rob
Marshall and adapted by Robin Swicord from the 1997 novel of the same name by Arthur Golden.
It tells the story of a young Japanese girl, Chiyo Sakamoto, who is sold by her impoverished family to a geisha house (okiya) to support them by training as and eventually becoming a geisha under the
pseudonym "Sayuri Nitta." The film centers around the sacrifices and hardship faced by pre-World War II geisha, and the challenges posed to geisha society by the war and a modernizing world.
It stars Zhang Ziyi in the lead role, with Michelle Yeoh, Gong Li, Youki
Kudoh, Suzuka Ohgo, Samantha Futerman and Ken Watanabe.
The film was produced by Steven Spielberg (through production companies Amblin Entertainment
and DreamWorks Pictures) and Douglas Wick (through Red Wagon Entertainment).
Production was split between southern and northern California and a number of locations
in Kyoto, including the Kiyomizu temple and the Fushimi Inari shrine.
It was released as a limited release in the United States on December 9, 2005, and a wide
release on December 23, 2005, by Sony Pictures Releasing (through Columbia Pictures).
The film was moderately successful at the box office and
garnered polarized reviews from critics worldwide.
The acting, visuals, sets, costumes, and musical score (composed by Spielberg's long-time collaborator John Williams) were praised, but the
film was criticized for casting some non-Japanese actresses as Japanese women and for its style over substance approach.
It was also nominated for and won numerous awards, including nominations for six Academy Awards, and
eventually won three: Best Cinematography, Best Art Direction and Best Costume Design.
Zhang was also nominated for the Golden Globe Award, Screen Actors
Guild Award, and the BAFTA Award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of secret love, japan,
prostitute, sibling relationship, geisha.
The tone is emotional.